Guide to the Henry S. Kaplan Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Henry S. Kaplan papers
circa 1960-1983
SC0317
Kaplan, Henry S., 1918-1984
35 Linear feet
Professional and administrative correspondence; research and clinical abstract files, and research notebooks; films; biographical material including an oral history interview; and other files.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research. Materials marked with asterisk (*) throughout collection are restricted for 75 years from date of creation, and are housed in Series IX, Box 1.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Radiologist, cancer research pioneer and educator. Henry S. Kaplan, 1918-1985, began his teaching career at the Stanford University School of Medicine in 1948. He served as professor and chair of the Dept. of Radiology (1948 to 1972) and was named D'Ambrogio Professor of Radiology in 1975. He also served as director of the Cancer Biology Research Laboratory (1975 to 1985) and the Biophysics Laboratory (1957 to 1962) at Stanford. Kaplan was best known for his work on leukemia and Hodgkins disease and for his work with Edward Ginzton on the development of the medical linear accelerator for cancer treatment. Kaplan's honors were international and numerous, among them the distinction of first radiologist elected to the National Academy of Science. In 1984, the Stanford Board of Trustees created the Henry S. Kaplan Professorship in Cancer Biology in recognition of his major contributions to the University and to society.
Description of the Collection
The Henry S. Kaplan papers include professional and administrative correspondence focusing prilnarily on his cancer research and the activity of the cancer Biology Research laboratory, research and clinical abstract files, research notebooks, films, correspondence concerning human rights and activities in Israel, biographical material including an oral history interview, and other files. The collection spans the years 1960 to 1983, covering his work at Stanford University as professor and chair of the Department of Radiology, as D'Ambrogio Professor of Radiology, and as Director of the cancer Biological Research Laboratory.
Kaplan's extensive slide collection describing his experimental research is currently used for teaching and is maintained by the Department of Radiology, Stanford School of Medicine. Kaplan's records concerning the development of the medical accelerator "CLlNAC" are not a part of this collection (some materials regarding CLlNAC can be found, however, in the Edward Ginzton papers (SC 330). Kaplan's papers also do not include materials concerning his career with the Stanford Medical School before its move to the Stanford campus in 1959.
Access Terms
Kaplan, Henry S., 1918-1984; Stanford University. Cancer Biology Research Laboratory.; Stanford University. Department of Radiology. Faculty.; Stanford University. School of Medicine.; Cancer.; Science--History.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, Series 1
  - A, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adelson Fund, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alm, Gunnar, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Academy of Arts & Sciences, 1968-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Board of Radiology, 1949-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American College of Radiology, 1945-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Association for Cancer Research Awards Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Radium Society, 1973-1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Roentgen Ray Society, 1956-1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Society of Clinical Oncology, 1973-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Society of Therapeutic Radiologists, 1967-1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Association of University Radiologists, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - August, Jay Thomas, 1963-1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ba-Ben 1977-84 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ber-Bi 1977-84 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bagshaw, Malcolm A., 1956-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Beilinson Medical Center, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Berenblum, I., 1960-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Biohazards, Tumor Virus Biohazard Control sub-committee. (Box 2, Folder 4-7)
  - Bishop, J. Michael, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bj-Brec, 1977-82 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Becker, Yechiel (Visiting Professor at CBRL, 1978-1983) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bren-Bz, 1977-83 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bleehen, Norman, 1966-1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Boag, J. W., 1972-1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Braude, A. I., 1952-1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Boniver, Jaques, 1976-1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cancer Advisory Board, 1977-1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - C (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cancer: a comprehensive treatise (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cancer: a comprehensive treatise (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Cancer Biology, Graduate Degree in (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Carnes, William H.,1958-1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Carnes, William H.,1965-1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Carson, Dennis (collaborator in research grants) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Classics in Oncology (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Classics in Oncology (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cell Lines, Requests for (SU-Amb-1) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - C. Norman Coleman, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Constine, Louis S., III, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Cook, Wendy, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Crowley, Lawrence, M.D., 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Da- (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - De- (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Darwin, Jay A., 1961-1975 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - *DeCleve, Alain (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - DeCleve, Alain: Correspondence, 1972-1981 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - DeCleve, Alain: Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - *DeCleve, Alain: C. V. and Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - *DeCleve, Alain: Recommendation for Promotion (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - DeCleve, Alain: Travel Expense Forms (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - *DeCleve Appointment: Unsuccessful Candidates (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - *DeCleve Appointment: Unsuccessful Candidates (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Devita, Vincent, Director, NCI (1 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Devita, Vincent, Director, NCI (2 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Devita, Vincent, Director, NCI (3 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Devita, Vincent, Publications (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Devita, Vincent, Publications (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Diehl, Volker, Prof. Dr. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Djerassi, Carl, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Doggett, R. L. Scotte, 1960-1981 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Donors: Lymphoma Research Program (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Donors: Chicago Group (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Dedication Ceremonies, 4 October 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Donaldson, Sarah S., 1972-1980 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Dorfman, R. F., 1967-1976 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - E (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - E (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Albert Einstein Peace Prize Foundation, Wm. M. Swartz (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Equipment: Cell Sorter (FACS) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Equipment: Electron Microscope (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Einhorn, Jerzy, 1971-1983 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Epstein, Alan (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Epstein, Alan (2 0f 2) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Epstein, Alan: "Production of MAB's to Early Antigen--PNAS (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Epstein, Alan: MSTP (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Evans, Richard C., 1968-1981 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - F (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - F (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - *(Faculty) Advisory Board, confid. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Advisory Board (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Farber, Sydney, 1953-1966 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - FASEB, Amer. Soc. Biological Chemists (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - FASEB, Amer. Soc. Biological Chemists (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - FASEB, American Society Experimental Pathology (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Federation of American Scientists (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Feldman, Michael, 1964-1982* (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Ferrer, Jorge F., 1969-1982 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Ferrone, Soldano, 1980-1983 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Fogarty International Center, Scholars-in-Residence (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Fowler, J. F. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Finn, Olga (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Fuks, Zvi, M.D. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Ga-Gi (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Gallo, Robert C. (1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Gallo, Robert C. (2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Garland, L. Henry (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Geiken, H. J., Special Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Gelmann, Edward D. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - General Motors Cancer Research Foundation (1982) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - General Motors CRF: Awards Assembly, New York (9/26/1983) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - General Motors CRF: Policies and Procedures (9/1/1983) (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - General Motors CRF: Joseph Fortner (Misc.) (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - General Motors CRF: Awards Assembly, Washington DC (6/1983) (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - General Motors CRF: Assembly Meeting, New York (4/1983) (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - General Motors CRF: Policies and Procedures (10/1/1981) (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - General Motors CRF: Awards Ceremony, Washington DC (6/1982) (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - General Motors CRF: Assembly Meeting (5/1982) (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - General Motors CRF: Assembly Meeting (9/1981) (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - General Motors CRF: Awards Ceremony (6/1981) (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Gift and Donation-Related Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Glatstein, Eli (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Glatstein, Eli (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Goodenow, Robert S., Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Ginzton, E. L. (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Ginzton, E. L. (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Gj-Gz (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Glaser, Robert J., 1961-1970 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Glick, Jane (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Glick, Jane (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Greenberg, Peter, M.D., 1983, Stanford hematologist (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Greenberger, Joel, Bone Marrow Corres. 1979-1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Greene, Arthur E., 1981 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - *Grymes, Rosalind, A. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Gross, Ludwik, 1956-1973 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Ha- (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - He- (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Hi- (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Haas, Martin, 1975-1983 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Hammer, Armand (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Hanks, Gerald E., 1967-1979 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Harris, John W., 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Hayflick, Leonard (1 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Hayflick, Leonard (2 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Hayflick, Leonard (3 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Hayflick, Susan-Milton Rosenberg Correspondence Re. UVA (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Hazen Lita Annenberg, Awards for Excellence in Clinical Research (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Henning Berlin GMBH--H. G. Will Pharmaceuticals-Monoclonals (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Hecht, Frederick and Barbara K. McCaw - Southwest Biomedical Research Institute (1 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Hecht, Frederick and Barbara K. McCaw - Southwest Biomedical Research Institute (2 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - *Heller, Emmanuel, 1959-1975 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Heller: 2nd Data (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Henle, Werner, 1973-1984 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Heilman, Samuel, 1969-1976 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Hematologic Malignancies Internal Review Board (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Heppel, Leon A., 1955-1979 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Herring, David F., 1969-1973 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - HEW Grants Policy Statement (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Hiatt, Howard, 1957-1976 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Hilgers, Jo (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Hj-Hz (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Holder, Walter D., M.D., 1980-1982 Stanford S.M. Dept. of Surgery (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Horecker, Bernard, 1955-1972 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Horwitz, Moris, 1948-1975 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Huebner, Robert J., 1974-1977 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - I (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Institute for Medical Research: Board of Regents - Dr. Prehn (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Institute for Medical Research: Dr. Lewis Coriell (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - International Journal of Radiation Oncology, Biology, Physics (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - International Society of Radiotherapy (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - International Union Against Cancer (1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - International Union Against Cancer (2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - J (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Johnson, William C., 1957-1973 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Jones, Henry H., 1950-1973 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - K (1 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - K (2 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Kaneta, Koichi, 1962-1978 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Lectures (1 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Lectures (2 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Lectures (3 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Orientation Lecture, September 26, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Professional File (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Professional File, Appointments - Stanford University (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Professional File, Appointments - VA Hospital (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Professional File, Misc. Travel Reports (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Professional File, SUMC Cancer Research Center (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Annual faculty reports (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Atoms for Peace Award, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Biographical materials (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: China notebook, October 1977 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Clinical & Laboratory Records (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Continuing medical education (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: French Academy of Sciences (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Harvard correspondence (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Kettering Award (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Legion of Honor 1965 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Licenses (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: National Academy of Sciences, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Personal (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Personal, 1949-1963 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Retirement from Chair of Radiology (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Kaplan, Henry S.: Special accounts - Exec. Fund Suballocation (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Karnofsky, David A. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Kirschbaum, Arthur (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Klein, George (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Kriser, David B. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Kriser, visiting professorship (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Kyewski, Bruno (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - L (1 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - L (2 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Lasker, Albert: Medical Research Awards (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Latarjet, Raymond (1959-1974) (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Laugier, Alain (1962-1981) (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Law, Lloyd W. (1950-1974) (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory: Donner Laboratory Search Committee (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Levy, Ronald (1967-1980) (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Liese, Grover J. (1955-1972) (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Loevinger, Robert (1956-1966) (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - London, Irving (1954-1976) (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Lorenz, Egon (1948-1955) (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Luetje, Lucille and Joseph Edward Luetje Fund (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Ludwig Institute for Cancer Research (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Ludwig Institute for Cancer Research: Cambridge Branch, Dr. Carl Baker (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Ludwig Institute for Cancer Research: Reports and Papers (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Ludwig Institute for Cancer Research: Scientific Report, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Lyman, Richard W. (1978) (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Lymphoma (Human) Conference (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Ma (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Mc-Me (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - MacMahon, Brian, 1963-1975 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Mandel, Mrs. Fred Jr., 1981-1984 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Marder, Sumner N., 1949-1955 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Malko, Sandra, 1979-1983 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Marks, Paul A., 1979-1982 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Maruyama, Yosh, 1960-1981 (1 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Maruyama, Yosh, 1960-1981 (2 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Mayer, Louis B. Foundation (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Memorial Sloan-Kettering, Report of Radiation Therapy Committee, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Mf-Mo (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Minna, John, 1975-1982 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Mirda, Daniel P. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Mp-Mz (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Musshoff, K., 1971-1983 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - N (1 of 3) (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - N (2 of 3) (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - N (3 of 3) (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - National Academy of Sciences: General (1 of 4) (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - National Academy of Sciences: General (2 of 4) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - National Academy of Sciences: General (3 of 4) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - National Academy of Sciences: General (4 of 4) (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - National Academy of Sciences: Class IV (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - National Academy of Sciences: Section 41 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - National Academy of Sciences: Board of Editors, Proceedings (1 of 2) (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - National Academy of Sciences: Board of Editors, Proceedings (2 of 2) (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - National Council on Drugs (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - National Cancer Institute, Division of Cancer Treatment, Board of Scientific Counselors (1 of 3) (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - National Cancer Institute, Division of Cancer Treatment, Board of Scientific Counselors (2 of 3) (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - National Cancer Institute, Division of Cancer Treatment, Board of Scientific Counselors (3 of 3) (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - NCI-Div. of Cancer Treatment, Lung Cancer Program (1 of 2) (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - NCI-Div. of Cancer Treatment, Lung Cancer Program (2 of 2) (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Newell, Robert R., 1951-1966 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Nickson, James J., 1952-1976 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Niwa, Ohtsura, 1972-1983 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Northern California Cancer Council (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Northern California Cancer Program - NCOG. Dr. Stephen Carter (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Northern Calif. Radiotheraphy Assoc. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - O (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - *Olcott, Eric, W.: Appointment forms (Box 25)
  - Olcott, Eric, W.: Time sheets (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Olcott, Eric, W.: Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Old, Lloyd J., 1980-1984 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Olsson, Lennart (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Olstad, Reidun, 1982-1983 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Pa-Pl (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Po- (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Pr- (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Physicians for Social Responsibility, Dr. Howard Kornfeld (1 of 2) (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Physicians for Social Responsibility, Dr. Howard Kornfeld (2 of 2) (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Pi Mesons (1 of 3) (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Pi Mesons (2 of 3) (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Pi Mesons (3 of 3) (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Pi Meson Facility: Site Visit (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Pi Meson Facility: Search Committee for Program Manager (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Pi Meson Facility: List of Participants (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Pi Meson Facility: Research Grant (1 of 2) (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Pi Meson Facility: Research Grant (2 of 2) (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Pi Meson Facility: SMPG, Cryogenic, and Dosimetry Status Reports (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Pi Meson Facility: NSF Proposal (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - R (1 of 2) (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - R (2 of 2) (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Radiation Research Society (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Radiation Research Society: Annual Meetings (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Rad. Res. Soc.: Failla Memorial Lecturer (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Radiobiology: New Building (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Radiological Society of North America (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Radiologists, Requests for (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Radiology Departmental Research Funds (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Rigler, Leo G., 1949-1976 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Risk Assessment Conference (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Rosenthal, Peter, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Royston, Ivor, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Sa-Se (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Sf-Sj (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Sachs, Leo, 1959-1983 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - San Francisco Regional Cancer Foundation (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Sapirstein, Leo A. (1 of 2) (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Sapirstein, Leo A. (2 of 2) (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Sato, Chikako, 1969-1973 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Scott, Sir Oliver, 1958-1973 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Seldin, Donald W. (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Segal, Shraga (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Shimizu, C. Susan, 1952-1962 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Siegal, F. P. Application for NIH grant (Hodgkin's Disease) (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Siegal, Edward, 1966-1980 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Silini, Giovanni, 1961-1983 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Simone, Joseph V., 1976-1980 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Sk-Sta (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Ste-Sz (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Smith, Mitzi Briggs, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Smithers, David W., 1956-1979 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Solnik, Catherine, 1972-1974 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Southwest Biomedical Research Institute (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Southwest Biomedical Research Institute: Financial Statements (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Southwest Biomedical Research Institute: Board Meetings (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Sherman, Nate H. and Sherman Family Fund (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Stanford University, Facilities Plan and Funding Forecast, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - "A Guide to Computer and Information Technology Resources at Stanford" (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Stanford University: Advisory Board of the Senate (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Stanford University School of Medicine: Ad Hoc Committee on Cancer Programs (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Stanford University School of Medicine: Committee on Investigative Medicine (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Stanford University School of Medicine: Faculty Practice Plan (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Stanford University School of Medicine: Faculty Senate (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Stanford University School of Medicine, Hospital Modernization Project (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Stanford University School of Medicine: Children's Hospital Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Stevens, Mr. & Mrs. Ben (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Stewart, J. Robert, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Ta-Th (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Ti-Tz (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Tabor, Herbert, 1950-1977 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Teaching, General (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Teaching, Radiology 201: Biological Effects of Radiation (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Teaching, Radiology 14: Radiation Biology (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Teaching, Radiology 211: Cancer Biology (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Terry, William D., 1972-1981 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Thompson, Ronald, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Three Mile Island, President's Commission (1 of 2) (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Three Mile Island, President's Commission (2 of 2) (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Treves, Abraham J., 1974-1983 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Tubiana, Maurice., 1961-1982 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - U (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - UNESCO, Committee for an Effective (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Ury, Melvin C., Fund; Janice Ury (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - V (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Varmus, Harold E. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Von Gehr, Ann B. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Von Essen, Carl F., 1951-1975 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Wa-We (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Wf-Wz (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Weissbluth, Mitchell, 1963-1976 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Weissman, Irving (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Wente, Karl L.; Jean Wente (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Western Society for Clinical Research (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - White, Abraham, 1953-1978 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Wilson, Hugh M. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Witte, Owen (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Wolfson, Justin (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Wong, Agnes 1973-1974 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Wright, Eric A., 1958-1970 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - XYZ (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Yaffe, David, 1961-1965 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Zacharski, Leo, 1979-1981 (Box 35, Folder 12)
- Notebooks, Series 2
  - Murine Lymphoma, Experimental Program (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Epstein-Barr, Virus Studies (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - HBLV Retrovirus (Box 14, Folder 3)